askiitians.com 2019-05-21

# Privacy Policy - | askIITians

    Please read this privacy policy to learn more about the ways in which we use and protect your personal information. Privacy Policy describes the information, what askIITians collect from you and what may happen to that information. 

    Your privacy is very important to us. We uses procedural and technical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft, as well as against unauthorized access or disclosure, to protect your privacy, including firewalls and encryption. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. 

    By accepting the Privacy Policy and Terms & Conditions in registration or by visiting and using the Site, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

    If you are 13 are over but under the age of 18, you may use this Site and submit personal information to us only in conjunction with and under the supervision of your parents or guardians.

    ## Information we collect and how we use it

    Our primary purpose in collecting personal information from you is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our service to make your experience safer and easier. We use any information voluntarily you give us to enhance your experience in our site, which is to provide you with interactive or personalized elements on the sites and to better prepare future content based on your interests. We aggregate this tracking information to determine which areas of our site members like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.

    We only collect personal information about you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose.

    You can browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. If you choose to use our Site, we may require you to provide contact and identity information, billing information, and other personal information as indicated on the forms throughout the Site. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature.

    We use your credit card information to verify the accuracy of your name, address, and other information, as well as to bill you for your use of our services. In addition, under some circumstances, we may ask you for your credit card information or other additional financial information to validate your identity. We do not store credit card information.

    We automatically track certain information about you based upon your behavior on our Site. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our Site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our Site or not), your computer browser information, and your IP address.

    askIItians.com may disclose personally identifiable information about you to third parties when:We have to cooperate with the investigations of purported unlawful activities and when we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights and related property of askIITians.com and that of its visitors.

    "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing our services.  We use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

    Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

    You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. And you may be required to re-enter your password more frequently during a session.

    If you choose to buy or sell on the Site, we collect information about your buying and selling behavior. We also collect other users' comments and ratings about you, any course and tutor offerings you provide on the Site and any other content you provide on the Site, in our feedback area.

    If you choose to post comments to lessons, topics, discussions board and other areas of the Site, or leave feedback for other users, we will collect that information that you provide to us. We retain this information for the benefit of the Site—more information is available in the askIITians Terms and Conditions. If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

    We use your personal information to facilitate the services you request. We use personal information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Site to: resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; bill any amounts due from you; measure consumer interest in our products and services, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; At times we look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes, and in particular we may examine your personal information to identify users using multiple User ID's or aliases. We may compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions and for accuracy.

    We may use personal information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze Site usage, to improve our content and product offerings, and to customize the Site's content, layout, and services. These uses improve the Site and better tailor it to meet your needs, so as to provide you with a smooth, efficient, safe and customized experience while using the Site.

    You agree that we may also use your personal information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, are targeted to your interests, such as targeted advertisements, administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the Site. 

    ## Disclosure of Information:

    As a matter of policy, we do not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. However the following describes some of the ways that your personal information may be disclosed in the normal scope of business to provide our services.

    We aggregate (gather up data across all user accounts) personal information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to identify you personally. Certain information, such as your name, email address, password, and financial information are not disclosed to these third parties in a personally identifiable manner without your explicit consent.

    Your Username is displayed throughout the Site, and is therefore available to the public. All of your activities on the Site will be identifiable to your User ID. Other people can see your published content including lessons, tests, forum posting, questions, comments, courses and tutor offerings, your authority and so on. Therefore, if you associate your name with your User ID, the people you have revealed your name to will be able to personally identify your askIITians activities. 

    ## Links to other websites:

    Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites whether they are teachers or students on our Site or other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the personal information you disclose to them. and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

    ## Control of Your Password:

    You are responsible for all actions take with your User ID and password, including fees incurred by your account. Therefore, we do not recommend that you disclose your askIITians.com password to any third parties. If you choose to share your User ID and password or your personal information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions take with your account and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy before doing so. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password by going to your account page.

    ## Reviewing and Changing Your Personally Identifiable Information:

    Following registration, you can review and change some of the information you submitted during registration you must promptly update your information if it changes. Upon your request, we will deactivate your account and contact information from our active databases. To make this request, please send us an email at info@askIITians.com. Such information will be deactivated as soon as reasonably possible based upon your account activity and in accordance with our deactivation policy and applicable law.

    We will retain in our files some personal information you have requested to remove to prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our **Terms and Conditions** and comply with legal requirements as is permitted by law. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personal information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests. However, such personal information will be deactivated from public and member viewing and will only be available to select askIITians personal.

    **Note: askIItians.com may amend this policy from time to time. Our services are subject to change at any given time.  **

    **Contacting Us:**

    You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

      * Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes

      * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at [info@askIITians.com]

    If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices, please write to us at the following address: 

    Email us at: info@askiitians.com 

    Call us at: 0120-4616500
